<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rahul Shrivastava</title>
    <link>https://rahuloms.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rahul Shrivastava</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rahuloms.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Food Inflation in India</title>
      <link>https://rahuloms.github.io/post/inflation-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahuloms.github.io/post/inflation-in-india/</guid>
      <description>Consumer Food Price Index In light of the protest by farmers from Punjab and Haryana over the 3 Farm laws passed in September, I decided to take a look at Food Inflation. The Consumer Price Index (CPI) in India has gone through a few changes since 2010 - the base year has changed from 2010 to 2012. The Consumer Food Price Index is a component of the overall CPI comrising the basket of food and beverages and this component remains the the most important basket with a weight of 45.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Banking Transactions</title>
      <link>https://rahuloms.github.io/post/online-banking-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahuloms.github.io/post/online-banking-transactions/</guid>
      <description>Explosive Growth of Mobile Banking A few days ago, HDFC bank suffered an outage at one of their data centres resulting in a many of the bank&amp;rsquo;s services going down - card payments, UPI, ATMs, netbanking, IMPS, NEFT etc.
Digital infrastructure for the banks is strained from the rapid growth of mobile and online transactions in the country, growing at an even faster rate post onset of COVID-19 pandemic.
The first round of rapid growth of mobile banking can be seen in 2017 following the demonetisation in November 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
